<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<articles>
    <article>
        <title>The Value of Money</title>
        <img>images/value-of-money.jpg</img>
        <alt>Image of Plants in a Jar of Coins</alt>
        <desc>Money is only valuable to those who don't recognize Nature</desc>
        <text>Who and what determines the value of money? The Central Banks? Corporates? Governments? In my opinion, the systems and structures that have been set up in the world have impacted society and thus give money its value.

            In these times, the majority view money as most essential and is needed to survive, not realising what truly backs money up.

            All central banks have vaults of gold that provide the value of money. Gold is from the land. Gold used to be used to trade for items and food, before the creation of money as we understand it now. I believe if wetrace the origins of what actually gives value to money, they are food and land - basically Nature. Essentially if we understand that we essentially need land to be able to grow and harvest food, then money has no value.

            The value is us being able to live off the land with reverence, being healthy and happy.

            Money is only valuable to those who don’t recognise Nature as part of itself.
        </text>
    </article>

    <article>
        <title>GMO Food</title>
        <img>images/gmo-food.jpg</img>
        <alt>Image of Tomato being genetically modified</alt>
        <desc>GMO Foods support the corporate agenda</desc>
        <text>Compared to a few years back when common GMO foods were just corn, cotton, wheat, and soy, now there are more foods that are being genetically modified. The list has expanded to include papaya, zucchini, and even alfalfa. (Source: https://www.kimbertonwholefoods.com/most-common-gmos/)

            The reason for the rise of GMO is to feed the world population as the traditional or regeneratively grown foods do not produce enough to feed the world population. However, I feel this is untrue as so much food is thrown away that it can feed the world’s population and livestock included!

            It is estimated that more than 900 million tonnes of food is wasted every year (source:https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-56271385). If, on average, a person eats about 35 tonnes of food in a lifetime (Source: https://www.reference.com/world-view/much-food-person-eat-lifetime-1015c822087dfa41), the food wasted can
            feed more than 25.7million people at least! It can feed those without access to food easily.

            I feel the rise in GMO is to curb our food sovereignty and control our access to food. Fruits and vegetables that have been genetically modified either have no seeds or the seeds can’t be grown.

            Nature is extremely intelligent and ensures all living beings are sustainable. Every living being can recreate or reproduce. Nature also evolves to withstand the changes happening in the environment around them. All fruits or vegetables have seeds or some part of the plant that can be planted to reproduce their
            offsprings.

            If all of us bought traditionally grown foods and planted the seeds, eventually we would be self-reliant.This however can cause the big corporations to lose money. As such, with use unknowingly, or knowingly,purchasing genetically modified foods, we would not be able to plant the seeds and hence will not be self-reliant. We are then unconsciously coerced to rely on the very corporations that profit from us.

            As such, as consumers, I feel we should be aware of how our foods are grown and should demand for traditionally or regeneratively grown foods. I also feel it is extremely crucial that we start growing our own foods, even if it is one or two varieties of fruits or vegetables and we must expose children from a young age to connect with Nature and to learn to grow their own foods.
        </text>
    </article>

    <article>
        <title>The View of World in 2100</title>
        <img>images/futuristic_world.jpg</img>
        <alt>Image of Futuristic World</alt>
        <desc>Is this the future we seek?</desc>
        <text>This pandemic has propelled us further into technology - now relying on online shopping, drone delivery, online meetings, virtual meetings, food delivery, amongst others. There is literally no necessity to have brick and mortar stores anymore as we use and rely more on technology.

            Hence, it is only natural to foresee a world in 2100 where we probably live like the cartoon series Jetsons - self-flying cars, living in the clouds, robots picking after us, basically in a highly technological world.

            However, my wish and my view of the world in 2100 is the total opposite of what many may think. I feel with the pandemic, more of us understand the need to connect with Nature, as we are part of Nature. More of us have started planting our own foods and are slowly becoming more self-reliant. More of us have gone further
            away from cities to the rural areas.

            With so many catastrophes that are happening or threatening to happen, such as the effects of the change in climate, and potentially more viral attacks, I feel Nature will somehow balance itself and the world and everything will be reset to the very beginning.

            We will live in harmony and in symbiosis with Nature just like over indigenous and ancestral relatives. We will live with deep respect for the land and all beings and treat everything like they are part of us. We would view the natural world as separate from us, as most currently do, but we will see it as part of us!
            The soil, air, water, and all other living beings form part of our flesh. In fact, the word Nature wouldn’t even exist as we are part of it and wouldn’t know a word that separates
            it.

            This is a very idealistic view, but I truly believe Nature always corrects itself, and hence us, as we are part of Nature and right now, we are not looking after our family members, and hence ourselves.
        </text>
    </article>

</articles>